Inarazaki has decided to swap in their captain, Shinsuke Kitan.
Is it to strengthen their defense, Phil?
Could be.
Inarazaki does seem to be more stable defensively when he's on the court.
More mentally stable as well.
I probably shouldn't be the one to bring this up, but...
Hmm?
Isn't putting me into the game right now more of a passive and defensively focused move?
What?
No, bringing you in is how I create my best offense.
Look, the MIA twins are totally on point out there today.
Your presence is telling them that they better not even think about putting on the brakes.
Understand?
To be honest, I don't like that motto.
It's not like the only path is the one in front of you.
There's a difference between faith and difficulties and being reckless.
People like them, I don't understand.
But I can't deny that watching them makes my heart swell.
I'm not the kind of player that can turn the tide of a game.
These guys can't help running ahead, and I agree that I need to do everything I can to have their backs.
Come on, man, I can do it!
I suspect you're in the same boat.
I understand.
I don't know.
I think you're in the same boat.
I don't care.
叶わないから
リドマナと味わえない
過去一番に楽しいこと
足りないモッド 足りないトーク
ねえ増えてるんだろう
Say Say No!
今と今向き合って
堪能するよ現実
酸いも甘いも全部
異不不動の正面と探したいな
面白そうな喜べそうだよな
今をやめない味わい尽くして笑おう
笑ってやろうぜ
オデーバー
Rin! One more time!
I take it you're running out of gas.
You'd like that, huh?
That's long!
Chance fall!
Got it!
Synchronized attack!
We're not matching up.
The quick didn't go through!
That mistake's gonna hurt for Karasuno.
Dammit, it was too high.
Sorry about that.
Do not apologize.
I didn't jump high enough that time.
Being ready to hit the ball over with every jump.
Constantly making sure there's room for the approach.
Hinata does this every time?
All the time?
You were wrong.
I didn't gauge the height correctly.
It's my mistake.
I know you're trying to take responsibility,
but your face is saying something else.
Hey, are you good?
You really need to ask.
We're gonna get the next one!
Yeah!
I'm pretty sure you could've followed up on that last one.
Let's nail this one, guys!
Asahi Azamani's serving for Karasuno.
He is one of their stronger servers,
but I'd say he's only been nailing about half of his serves today.
So things are still up in the air.
We're getting to the end of the last set,
and Inarazaki's in the lead.
The pressure he's facing now is far greater than anything he's felt this far.
One hundred percent.
Bring it!
Yeah!
He did it!
That's Asahi Azamani determined to live up to his ace title!
What a flawless service ace!
Nice one, Asahi!
Push it, push it, Asahi!
Way to go, samurai pro!
Get that serve!
Oh god, this is not good.
Asahi, that was sick!
The Karasuno samurai started off at what?
Around 80%?
And has gotten more powerful as the match went on.
And now that it's down to the wire, he's ready to unleash it all.
Man, Samu, now I'm getting hungry.
Well, join the club.
One more time, guys!
Kitita!
Nice receive!
A powerful serve, but Captain Kitita bumps it up beautifully.
Oh man, I have no idea if I could have gotten that.
Who is that sumumiya going to set to this time?
Please come together.
Give him a strong two-man block.
Just like that!
Cover!
I got it!
Nice receive!
Man, what is this?
I'm feeling really good!
He's supposed to be in the back row!
Right now!
This moment right now is always the best chance!
Twin quick!
Minus tempo!
Reverse!
Nice day!
I don't want to lose.
I won't let them beat us.
I'm not going to let this end.
That's okay.
Just make sure and watch me get the next one!
I don't want to lose.
We have to win.
What kind of stupid, shallow ideas are those?
That's just talking about results.
Victory or defeat.
The overall concept doesn't change.
It's about this point, right now!
It's about dominating this fight.
Synchronized attack!
During their match with Shira Torizawa, they did an attack from the back a single time.
And today, they only did it once, as one of their tricks to stop Atsumu serving.
Is there really any point joining an attack if it means abandoning a position as backup?
I'm not out here just to protect my teammates.
Each and every one of us is here to score!
Aaaaah!
Eughh!
Hm!
Karasino manages to catch up to Inanazaki before they can run away with their lead.
The goddess of victory turns her eyes toward Karasino.
They have taken the lead.
The situation seemed pretty grim when they failed to get a break point after Hina to save.
But since that timeout, it seems like Karasino has gotten out from under what was weighing them down.
Damn, I was hot.
And Inanazaki scores again without batting an eye.
Mealtime is my favorite, but these eight seconds are next.
Cover!
Kageyama, yours!
He went straight at their Senate. Not a bad call.
Osamu!
Oh, it's that thing from earlier!
No.
That quick is too unstable.
I doubt they'd use it again in a spot like this.
Those twins, they're gonna do it.
You guys are thinking that too, aren't you?
Oh!
One and a half blockers!
And just like that, Inanazaki has taken the lead once more!
Yeah!
Nice kill.
Not bad, Samu!
Oh, yeah?
Yeah!
It looked like Karasino was distracted by Atsumu on the right side.
True, Phil.
No doubt they're worn out physically, but they're sure to be mentally exhausted as well.
I need some carbs right about now.
Tanaka!
Three blockers!
Nice!
Well done!
Yes, yes, yes!
Great job!
Nice kill!
Yeah!
Tsukashima and Hinata still aren't the best servers.
So we have to accept that we might give up a point during this rotation.
But that's also why, if they do get the breakpoint...
Alan!
I got it!
Touch the ball!
And a center dunk!
That one really came out of nowhere!
Oh, hell yeah!
Right!
Just move on!
No use crying about that one!
Just as Inanazaki's Kita moves to the front, they're returning Ginjima to the court!
Yes!
First a brutal server, then Gijima slams the down for the point!
Hell yeah!
And Inanazaki is just one step away from the win!
Nice kill, Hitoshi!
Jump, jump, Hitoshi!
One more time!
Keep your cool, Mal!
We'll get that point!
Just stay focused!
You've got this, dammit!
I don't care how tired you are!
And I don't care how tough they are!
I don't care how tough they are!
One more time!
Keep your cool now!
Well get that point!
Just stay focused!
You've got this dammit!
I don't care how tired you are!
And I don't care how tough they are!
And guess what?
Nobody cares how hard you've been working so far!
You have to keep working harder!
This is...
This is crazy!
It feels so weird!
I think I'm on a roll right now!
I feel like I'm even seeing blocks better than normal!
Maybe that's why...
Why my instincts are telling me...
Not to go any harder!
Kageyama...
It hurts to ask you to do this, but...
Could you...
Hold off on sending to me for a little while?
Huh?
No chance!
Kama!
Tanaka!
Kageyama!
An unexpected quick attack from Karasuno!
But Ojiro still manages to get the ball in the air!
They're not gonna be able to get a decent attack!
Oh, wow!
Both of these setters are among the top in the nation!
They're showing us some extremely high-level play!
No chance!
We're gonna need your attacks, Tanaka!
That punk...
Wasn't just trying to make me feel better!
Kageyama!
It's normal not to know what other people are feeling!
Your jobs are the following things!
To know how the game is going, and how your teammates are doing!
Since the end of the first set, Tanaka has definitely been doing alright!
He's been staying calm at times when he'd usually fly off the handle!
That extreme cut shot he pulled off was awesome too!
But...
Is that really the best weapon Tanaka has in his arsenal?
Everyone on our team is good at what they do!
That...
Is not for me to decide!
They've kept it going through so many insane plays!
It's the end of the match, the rallies are long, the receives are getting sloppy!
Now more than ever, there's no longer short, no near or far, not anymore!
The set is moving beautifully toward the antenna!
Go farther!
Go to the very edge!
Give the Spikers...
More options!
Ever since that extreme cut shot...
It's subtle, but the blockers are definitely watching out for crosses!
Tanaka wrenched open another path for us!
He wasn't just trying to make me feel better!
He trusts me!
And I won't let him down!
He nailed that!
An extreme line shot!
I can't believe how straight that line shot was, Phil!
You know it!
Rinusuke Tanaka scores the point with an incredible spike!
That was a fantastic shot!
Based on his positioning, I was sure it would be another cross!
Oh man, that was awesome!
Not many at all!
Yeah!
Hey!
Nice set, man!
Sure!
Nice kill!
What the...
Where the hell did the goody two-shoes go?
What happened to him in the last few weeks?
That's Ryunosuke Tanaka from Karasano High School!
With one smash, he sliced right through in Narazaki's positive energy!
What a weirdo!
Honey, that's rude!
What the...
Where the hell did the goody two-shoes go?
What happened to him in the last few weeks?
That's Ryunosuke Tanaka from Karasano High School!
From Karasano High School!
With one smash, he sliced right through in Narazaki's positive energy!
Dush!
Huh?
What a weirdo!
Honey, that's rude!
Fush!
What a weirdo!
Karasano shows no signs of slowing down, but in Narazaki is still at match point!
If he commits a service error or gives them a soft serve, all that's waiting for this team is bitter defeat!
I know I don't need to shield my head...
But...
I still want to do it anyway!
Ugh!
What the hell's he doing, Atsumu?
Ah!
Did you see those nerves of steel?
That unbreakable concentration!
And amazing service ace that ties them up once again!
Incredible stuff from Tobio Kageyama!
Alright!
I'm beyond impressed, now I'm just infuriated.
Huh?
Come on, let's go!
Oh...
Seriously...
His game today...
Up front!
At the very last possible second, Kageyama seemed to know exactly what the receivers were thinking and dropped the serve up front!
Chance ball's mine!
With lightning speed, Karasano gets one right down the middle!
Yeah!
They saw the other team panic and did not waste the opportunity!
That middle shot moved at a ridiculous speed!
Now it's Karasano who's one step away from victory!
You only get to be the ace if you can both attack and defend!
And Kageyama scores one like it's a walk in the park!
Even though everyone is exhausted at this point, they didn't give the blockers the slightest hint where they were going!
What a beautiful set!
We're so close to the end of the match, but he's still on his game!
The way Atsumu sets the ball out there, it's like somehow deep inside, he knows the other team's thoughts!
He must be a genius!
It's tough playing the same position!
I've noticed Kageyama's serves are scary good too!
I wish I had that kind of talent!
I don't remember when, but someone asked me once, if as a second string player, it ever bothered me to have all these genius players on the same team who are younger than I am!
I don't know what the true definition of a genius is, but I did know what they were trying to say!
Sometimes you run into people in the world, who think a guy like Atsumu was just somehow born with incredible talent for no reason.
That's wrong.
If what I do every day is going from 1 to 10, then guys like Atsumu are going from 1 to 20.
Or maybe like a more effective 10, or a weightier 10.
Sometimes they think, what if I don't go from 1 to 10?
I mean, that can't be the only way to do what I'm trying to do.
It would be pretty interesting if I tried going from A to Z instead.
Even if they mess up, or people start to hate them.
Or if it means trampling all over something we all think is valuable and important.
They just have to do it.
These guys are who, even if they start coughing up blood, they still want to keep running so bad they can't stop.
One touch!
There are plenty of people in the world who will make you think you'll never match up to them.
And of course you're going to be impressed by those guys, because that's a natural reaction.
I think it's a talent to be able to rush ahead at full speed.
And it doesn't really matter what you call these people.
The word genius isn't an insult after all.
But, that said, if you think of them as better than you from the moment of birth,
you've given them the whole game before you've even stepped on the court.
And you're also being rude.
And Karasuma receives the ball again!
What an epic rally! A true battle of wills!
Damn it! Just five more centimeters! You can reach that! Jump higher! Reach it!
Damn it!
Off his foot! Shuyo Hinata demonstrates formidable balance and skill!
Karasuna narrowly manages to stop Inadozaki from scoring a breakpoint!
Oh wow! I'm sure young Hinata and the ball have spent a lot of time together here!
Damn it! Don't get exhausted now!
I know you didn't mean anything by it. Sorry for the rain. It was a sore spot.
No, uh, in this case, I think it's kinda worse that I didn't mean anything by it.
That may be more than my brain can handle.
Complaint, dumbass!
Complaint about what?
Give me one more!
I honestly thought nothing really scared Kageyama anymore.
But it's not only the people across enemy lines that could push you all the way to your limit.
I'm impressed, Hinata.
With the
Thank you.
Next time, the monster's ball.